Guide to the Frank Barry papers, 1975-2000.
Barry, Frank
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Frank Barry papers, 1975-2000.
23-13-3297
Frank D. Barry
2 cubic ft.
Newsletters, reports, curriculum, and films.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Senior Extension Associate in the Family Life Development Center, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Curriculum and conference material, correspondence, reports, project proposals, films, and publications concerning work done in the Family Life Development Center (FLDC) concerning child abuse and neglect, specifically ACT (Assets Coming Together) for Youth, a project of the New York State Dept. of Health; the Community Lifelines Program; Statewide Teamwork for Abused Runaways (STAR); and reports written by Barry for the United States Advisory Board on Child Abuse and Neglect. Includes two films, "Child Abuse: A Total Treatment Perspective" and "Child Abuse: Perspective on Being a Parent".
SUBJECTS
Names:
Barry, Frank D.; Barry, Frank D.; Assets Coming Together (ACT) for Youth.; Community Lifelines Program; New York (State).Dept. of Health.; New York (State).Dept. of Health.; New York State College of Human Ecology.Family Life Development Center.; Statewide Teamwork for Abused Runaways (STAR).; United States Advisory Board on Child Abuse and Neglect.
Subjects:
Child abuse--Prevention.; Child abuse--United States.; Abusive parents--United States.; Family violence.; Child welfare--United States.; Child abuse--New York (State)--Investigation.; Child abuse--Law and legislation--New York (State)--Handbooks, manuals, etc.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Family Life and Development Center Events and Projects
Box 1, folders 1-12, 28; Box 2, folder 26
Series II. FLDC Conferences and Curriculum/Publications
Box 1, folders 26-27; Box 2, folders 1-2, 24-25, 27-28
Series III. Regional Resource Center on Child Abuse and Neglect
Box 1, folders 13-20
Series IV. United States Advisory Board on Child Abuse and Neglect
Box 2, folders 21-25
Series V. Community Lifelines Program
Box 2, folders 3-11
Series VI. Statewide Teamwork for Abused Runaways
Box 2, folders 12-16
Series VII. Rural Services Training Project
Box 2, folders 17-20
Series VIII. Cornell Collaboration and Community Building Curriculum Training
Box 2, folders 21-23
Series IX. Films
Box 30, collection 21-36-2566
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Family Life and Development Center--Events and Projects
  - Important Events, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Important Events, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Important Events, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence-testimonial letters, 1980-1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - NYS Resource Center-first federal grant reports and conference information, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Child Abuse and Neglect Task Forces, 1975-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Training for Task Forces, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - System for Ranking Counties according to Child Abuse and Neglect, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - First Research Project-FLDC-The NYS Central Register for Child Abuse and Neglect: An exploration of Research Potential-by Maxine Schaggen, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Evaluation of NY's Abuse Reporting Law of 1973, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Legislative Resolution Adopted in Assembly, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Storytelling Project in NYC, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Series II: FLDC Conferences and Curriculum/Publications
  - "What's a Kid to do About Child Abuse?" and "What Happens Next?"-Margo Hittleman, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "What's a Teacher to Do?"-program geared toward migrant children, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Curriculum on Child Abuse and Neglect for Children and Youth--K-6 grades (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Search Conferences in Lyons, Ovid, Utica, Groton, 1997; 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Child Abuse Guidelines for Parent; "Children, Alligators and Spotted Owls"-presentation by Frank Berry, 1992; 1999 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - "Parents and School Partnerships for Preventing Child Abuse"-a handbook used in Bronx Schools, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - VHS "Hardscrabble Childhood, Growing up poor in rural New York"-video produced by FLDC--rural poverty from a child's perspective. Use copy DVD #595 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "A Community Handbook on Child Abuse and Neglect, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Series III: Regional Resource Center on Child Abuse and Neglect
  - Regional Resource Center Proposal, 11978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Quarterly Reports, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Quarterly Reports, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Quarterly Reports, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Quarterly Reports, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Quarterly Reports, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Quarterly Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Final Report; Corresponsdence Concerning sx abuse, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series IV: United States Advisory Board on Child Abuse and Neglect
  - "Neighborhood Based Approach, What is it?" by Frank Barry (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Critical First Steps in Response to a National Emergency", 1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Creating Caring Communities"-2nd Report, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "The Continuing Child Protection Emergency"-3rd Report, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Neighbors Helping Neighbors"-4th Report, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Protecting Children from Abuse and Neglect"-book publishing findings of Advisory Board, 1994 (Box 1)
- Series V: Community Lifelines
  - Final Report, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Evaluation Report, 1994; Parent Partner Manual,1994; Draft of Federal Evaluation Project, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - In school district in Spencer Van Etten, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Original proposal and workplans, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Quarterly Reports, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Quarterly Reports, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Radio Broadcasts, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
- Series VI: Statewide Teamwork for Abused Runaways (STAR)
  - Quarterly Reports, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Buddy Training System-Workbook Manual, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Buddy Training System-Resource Manual, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Buddy Training System-Video (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Project manual by Frank Barry and letter, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Understanding Survivors of Abuse"-book by Jane Levine Powers and Barbara Weiss Jaklitsch, 1989 (Box 2)
- Series VII: Rural Services Training Project
  - Final Reports, 1988-1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Manuals, 1990-1999 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Forums, 1988-1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Advisory Committee, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Series VII: Cornell Collaboration and Community Building Curriculum Training
  - Quarterly and Final Reports, 1988-2000 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Quarterly and Final Reports, 1988-2000 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Final Report, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Series IX: Films
  - "Child Abuse: Perspective on Being a Parent", 1975-1980 (Box 30 (collection #21/36/2566))
  - "Child Abuse: A Total Treatment Perspective, 1975-1980 (Box 30 (collection #21/36/2566))